<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 11:45:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Celebrating a Major Community Milestone: #WeAre1Million!</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-major-community-milestone-1-million/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-major-community-milestone-1-million/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 15:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sabrina Maréchal]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21293</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Yes, you read it right: today the PrestaShop Community passed the one-million-member mark! For the past 9 years, our community has been growing and supporting the PrestaShop adventure. Let’s take a look at how we got this far together! We spent the last several weeks digging through our archives, looking at our top contributors’ stats, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-major-community-milestone-1-million/">Celebrating a Major Community Milestone: #WeAre1Million!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, you read it right: today the PrestaShop Community passed the one-million-member mark! For the past 9 years, our community has been growing and supporting the PrestaShop adventure. Let’s take a look at how we got this far together!</p>
<p><span id="more-21293"></span></p>
<p>We spent the last several weeks digging through our archives, looking at our top contributors’ stats, and giggling at old photos. Did you know, for example, that Bruno was only 23 when he founded PrestaShop?! In fact, most of the team members were in their early 20’s… <em>(Stay tuned for a Throwback Thursday article!)</em></p>
<p>It’s no secret that PrestaShop is where it is today because of our incredible Open-source community: together we’ve released a ton of products, held numerous events, and welcomed so many contributions from incredible contributors around the world.</p>
<p>To really get a sense of what we’ve accomplished together, we created a timeline of our Community’s history going back to 2007 and identified 40 of our most committed contributors who hail from 24 countries. They’re either Forum Superstars, GitHub Legends, Translation Gurus or Addons Masters, and they’ve all had an impact on the Community’s development.</p>
<p>Take a stroll with Preston as he walks&#8211;or, rather, flies&#8211;down memory lane and meet these exceptional members along the way.</p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #fcbb23; border: 1px solid #fcbb23; border-bottom: 3px solid #e9a621; margin: 20px 0 0; color: #fff;" href="http://weare1million.prestashop.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=blog-post&amp;utm_campaign=weare1million&amp;utm_content=blog-post-launch-EN" target="_blank"><i class="fa fa-key"></i>   Discover the PrestaShop Community History</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more articles as we:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px;">
<li>Introduce you to our 40 historic members (March 22<sup>nd</sup>)</li>
<li>Present our millionth member (March 29<sup>th</sup>)</li>
<li>Host a very special Throwback Thursday (March 31<sup>st</sup>)</li>
<li>Explain why Open-source is so powerful (April 5<sup>th</sup>)</li>
</ul>
<p>For a chance to receive a super-exclusive-ultra-limited edition T-shirt (<em>for real &#8211; we’ve only got 10!</em>), download <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/download/pdf/WeAre1Million.pdf" target="_blank">this poster</a>, take an epic snapshot with it and share it on Twitter with #WeAre1Million and tag @PrestaShop. Who knows, you just might be a winner! <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<p>We hope you enjoy our little stroll down memory lane. Now let’s get ready to welcome the 2,000,000<sup>th</sup> member!</p>
<p>We ❤ you!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-major-community-milestone-1-million/">Celebrating a Major Community Milestone: #WeAre1Million!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-major-community-milestone-1-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Increase sales by selling on US-based Jet Marketplace</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/increase-sales-selling-us-based-jet-marketplace/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/increase-sales-selling-us-based-jet-marketplace/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 14:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaux Choplin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21331</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Selling on marketplaces can be a fast, effective way for ecommerce stores to boost sales. Amazon, Alibaba, eBay, and Etsy are a few examples of well-known marketplaces that generate massive online sales around the world. Diversifying the marketplaces where your store is present allows you to target different audiences to gain traffic and visibility. That’s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/increase-sales-selling-us-based-jet-marketplace/">Increase sales by selling on US-based Jet Marketplace</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Selling on marketplaces can be a fast, effective way for ecommerce stores to boost sales. Amazon, Alibaba, eBay, and Etsy are a few examples of well-known marketplaces that generate massive online sales around the world. Diversifying the marketplaces where your store is present allows you to target different audiences to gain traffic and visibility. That’s where Jet.com can give you a boost.<br />
<span id="more-21331"></span><br />
Each country is dominated by local e-commerce players: in France, this is Cdiscount; in Brazil, it’s MercadoLivre; in India, Flipkart; and in Russia, Ulmart. Now, the United States has Jet.com, a newcomer with a lofty goal that will help small merchants reach their own sales objectives. Launched in July 2015, Jet.com’s goal is to overtake Amazon and reach over $20 billion in Gross Merchandise Volume by 2020. </p>
<p>According to <em>The Washington Post</em> and <em>TechCrunch</em>, <strong>Jet.com became the fourth most popular marketplace in the United States</strong> in term of Gross Merchandise Value in August 2015, just a month after its launch. Even better, the company announced $33 million in sales and 1 million customers in November, with 23% identified as repeat customers. With millions of loyal customers already convinced, Jet.com is, in their own word, a “fair marketplace that removes inefficiency and cost resulting in the best value for shoppers with improved margins and greater control over order profitability for retailers.”</p>
<p>So what does this mean for merchants? There’s a new marketplace with an eager audience that is coming back again and again to do its shopping. So it’s a great time to get onboard with Jet.com by integrating the brand new <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/22098-jet-marketplace.html" target="_blank">dedicated module</a> developed with help from our <a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/integration-fund" target="_blank">Integration Fund</a> program. Built by <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/58_common-services" target="_blank">Common Services</a>, one of our contributors specializing in marketplaces, the Jet.com module enables you to easily export your catalog and run your items on Jet.com, as well as to synchronize your orders with your PrestaShop back-office. If you already sell on Amazon or other marketplaces, then you won’t find any surprises. If you’re new to marketplaces, this module is simple to start using. </p>
<p>Jet.com has many advantages for retailers who choose to sell on its marketplace: free shipping from a certain amount, free returns, as well as a full range of quantity-based discounts. All of which contributes to higher Average Order Volume on the Jet marketplace. Jet.com also offers ways to cut costs thanks to a dynamic pricing engine that works to give the best margin possible. </p>
<p>Jet.com is on its way up and it’s taking merchants with it. There’s a great opportunity to reach a new audience and be one of the first merchants to establish a presence on the marketplaces; <strong>stores who have joined are already reporting earning up to 5% of sales from the marketplace</strong>. For the moment, PrestaShop is the only ecommerce software provider for SMBs that offers a module for Jet. </p>
<p>So give it a try and let us know what you think!</p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/22098-jet-marketplace.html" target="_blank">Find out more about the Jet.com module</a> </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/increase-sales-selling-us-based-jet-marketplace/">Increase sales by selling on US-based Jet Marketplace</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/increase-sales-selling-us-based-jet-marketplace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 simple steps to optimize your online shop’s performance</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-simple-steps-to-optimize-your-online-shops-performance/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-simple-steps-to-optimize-your-online-shops-performance/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21241</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Many merchants just starting out know metrics are important, but fewer monitor their performance closely right from the beginning. Unfortunately, this means they are missing out on valuable data that could make an impact on business decisions, and ultimately, success. Today’s video from the experts Business Tech shows you how to optimize performance through metrics [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-simple-steps-to-optimize-your-online-shops-performance/">4 simple steps to optimize your online shop’s performance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many merchants just starting out <em>know</em> metrics are important, but fewer monitor their performance closely right from the beginning. Unfortunately, this means they are missing out on valuable data that could make an impact on business decisions, and ultimately, success. Today’s video from the experts <a href="http://www.businesstech.fr/en/content/10-business-tech-4l3p-ecommerce" target="_blank">Business Tech</a> shows you how to optimize performance through metrics in four simple steps:<br />
<span id="more-21241"></span></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Setting objectives</li>
<li>Identifying KPIs</li>
<li>Using dedicated analytics tools</li>
<li>Online store optimization</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0acJfI8fn-0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop" target="_blank" style="background-color: #E62117;border: 1px solid #E62117;border-bottom: 3px solid #CC181E;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff">Subscribe to our Youtube Channel for more videos</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-simple-steps-to-optimize-your-online-shops-performance/">4 simple steps to optimize your online shop’s performance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-simple-steps-to-optimize-your-online-shops-performance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PIM: go further and faster in managing your product data</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/pim-go-faster-managing-product-data/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/pim-go-faster-managing-product-data/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 08:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21317</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In today’s article, our partner agency Synolia explains how open source Product Information Management tools like Akeneo can help retailers streamline product catalogs and communicate more effectively with customers. After a decade spent going toe-to-toe, traditional and digital distribution channels are now coming together to better meet customers’ needs. From a multi-channel strategy&#8230; Today, an [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/pim-go-faster-managing-product-data/">PIM: go further and faster in managing your product data</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>In today’s article, our partner agency Synolia explains how open source Product Information Management tools like Akeneo can help retailers streamline product catalogs and communicate more effectively with customers.</em></p>
<p><strong>After a decade spent going toe-to-toe, traditional and digital distribution channels are now coming together to better meet customers’ needs.</strong><br />
<span id="more-21317"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#663b8f">From a multi-channel strategy&#8230;</h2>
<p>Today, an e-commerce website is a real driver of traffic and revenue for traditional networks, at least for those retailers who use it correctly.<br />
Web-to-store, web-in-store…more and more web retailers are implementing e-commerce features intended to drive part of their clientele, who would otherwise have been lost, to physical networks. </p>
<p>But having an online catalog is one thing; <em>selling</em> online is altogether another.</p>
<p>Today, redirecting a customer looking for an out-of-stock product to a point of sale, or letting a customer prepare their product online and then collecting it in-store is much more effective than simply limiting customers to what is available in one channel or another.</p>
<p>It can be a lever for increasing revenue when tied to a brand image that is uniformly presented across all distribution channels. It also allows for the e-commerce channel to be integrated into the traditional distribution network. </p>
<h2 style="color:#663b8f">&#8230;to a customer-centric experience!</h2>
<p>The multiplication of distribution channels brings new constraints to managing and administering a product catalog that demand tailored solutions.<br />
Until now, most channels have been used in tandem, but with separate catalogs. </p>
<p>The paper channel &#8211; whose flagship remains the catalog &#8211; was usually handed over to a communications agency, who would spend weeks, or even months, every year manually aggregating various data in InDesign. </p>
<p>The store network was usually content with data from external software solutions (ERPs) for information about stocks and prices. The e-commerce channel, for its part, juggled with its ERP and rather archaic data enrichment tools (Excel files, for example) to obtain a somewhat-usable feed to build and enrich an online catalog. </p>
<p>The end result was a clutter of multiple, heterogeneous data sources, and resources that did and redid the same work each year without benefiting from an economy of scale. The result: unstructured data that was impossible to use across channels. </p>
<p><strong>But that was before!</strong></p>
<h2 style="color:#663b8f">Long live the PIM!</h2>
<p>The expansion of omni-channel sales has imposed a radical change in how product catalogs are used and resulted in the develop of PIM: <strong>Product Information Management</strong>. </p>
<p>PIM offers 3 concrete solutions: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Collecting and centralizing data</strong></li>
<li><strong>Enriching and maintaining this information</strong></li>
<li><strong>Sharing catalogs, adapted to different distribution channels</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Let’s take a look at a concrete example of what you can do with <strong>Akeneo</strong>, an <strong>Open Source PIM</strong> platform that is quickly becoming a leader in the market, in the context of multiple distribution channels that include an e-commerce channel represented by a PrestaShop retail site.  </p>
<h4 style="color:#663b8f">Collect product information to create a single foundation</h4>
<p>The PIM application lets you combine product data feeds, no matter their origin, to create a reliable, up-to-date product referential. Just as an ERP provides a central point for order processing, PIM is fast becoming the point of reference for product databases, and contains all the information needed to inform various distribution channels. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/03/collect.png" alt="collect" width="369" height="337" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21320" /></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong style="color:#663b8f">Collect Data</strong>
<ul style="margin: 0 0 16px">
<li>Collect product data <strong>from existing sources</strong> (ERP, local files, vendors POs)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong style="color:#663b8f">Automate imports</strong>
<ul style="margin: 0 0 16px">
<li><strong>Integrate an open source PIM like Akeneo</strong> to automate data imports</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 style="color:#663b8f">Enrich data to improve the customer experience</h4>
<p>Next comes the enrichment phase. PIM provides a user-friendly interface to manage catalog enrichment by adding cold information, which consists of attributes that are either shared among channels or specific to each one (<em>i.e. data that does not change according to criteria such as discounts, which are usually managed by an ERP</em>). PIM also helps manage all media, such as product images, that present specific constraints depending on the distribution channel. For example, an image used online doesn’t need to be the same resolution as one shown in a print catalog, even if the source is the same: that’s why the PIM automatically manages and converts these media &#8211; resizing, processing, etc.</p>
<p>To effectively enrich a product, you need to have visibility into your catalog. PIM can offer a lot of flexibility in this area and help save time by allowing you to track your catalog status, channel-by-channel. In real life, this means knowing, for example, that product X can be published on the FR retail site, but that something is still in translation for the UK version, or that an additional attribute needs to be entered for the print catalog for professionals.</p>
<p>Using profile management combined with approval work flows, PIM allows you dedicate team resources to certain tasks or channels, and direct others to approving the enrichment work you’re doing. This collaborative mode can save you a lot of time when you’re managing your catalog, something you can only dream about if you handle product references using a multitude of files sent to various staff members before approval. </p>
<p>The bottom line: you’ll end up managing a catalog of a much higher quality faster and more efficiently, thereby improving your brand image.</p>
<p>In the projects that we have completed over the last few months, we’ve noticed increases of around 50% between the catalog volume that the retailer had hoped to manage, and that they actually handled in the same period of time, with fewer resources! This represents a significant time savings and reduced <strong>time-to-market</strong>. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/03/enrichir.png" alt="enrichir" width="388" height="274" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21322" /></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong style="color:#663b8f">Enrich data</strong>
<ul style="margin: 0 0 16px">
<li>Integrate <strong>marketing</strong></li>
<li><strong>Adapt data</strong> to the distribution channel</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong style="color:#663b8f">Maintain and translate</strong>
<ul style="margin: 0 0 16px">
<li><strong>Keep information up to date</strong> in a single back office</li>
<li><strong>Translate data</strong> for adaptation</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 style="color:#663b8f">Easily share catalogs adapted to your distribution channels</h4>
<p>Once this enrichment work has been completed, you can communicate your product data across distribution channels automatically. </p>
<p>Here the PIM really shines, since it not only feeds into digital channels (E-commerce, Mobile), but also automatically fills InDesign templates, accomplishing 90% of the design work required to produce a paper catalog. Figures given to us by the print specialists we work with are enlightening: where a large catalog used to take 6 months, the work can now be completed in a few weeks, with 50% fewer resources and the same quality result. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/03/controler.png" alt="controler" width="407" height="443" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21321" /></p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong style="color:#663b8f">Control distribution</strong>
<ul style="margin: 0 0 16px">
<li>All sales channels with a single solution (<em>e-commerce, paper catalogs, mobile applications, social media, marketplaces and more</em>)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong style="color:#663b8f">Manage export</strong>
<ul style="margin: 0 0 16px">
<li>Select <strong>data</strong> to export by channel</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color:#663b8f">The advent of Open Source PIM!</h2>
<p>Until recently, Product Information Management platforms were reserved for large retailers who managed very large volumes and had the financial resources to pay licensing fees amounting to several hundreds of thousands of dollars or euros. </p>
<p>With the advent of Open Source PIMs like Akeneo, this type of platform has become very affordable, and any business with several broadcasting channels now ought to take a close look at a PIM that will place itself upstream of the information system alongside the ERP. </p>
<p>It’s a small revolution in the distribution world, where the exactness of the (product) information that is given has become a real issue. Beyond the purely financial gains, PIM also provides a unifying element that can been a boon to businesses confronted with a lack of consistency in product data and dispersed information: it can all be profitably centralized through a PIM. </p>
<p>Product pages with quality content will generate benefits in SEO, as well as the customer experience: with a properly filled out product page, visitors have all of the information they need to evaluate the product and its characteristics. With information at hand and questions answered, they are also more likely to add items to their cart and complete their order.</p>
<p>The true impact comes into focus when looked in light of FEVAD figures, which estimate that currently 80% of the world’s e-commerce data is wrong because it is not adapted to the communication channel. <strong>By delivering the right message, you can potentially gain an advantage over 80% of your direct competitors.</strong></p>
<p>This won&#8217;t be the last you hear of PIM, which is sure to become a vital element of any retail project. The solutions are easy to implement for an almost immediate ROI and vital working comfort for the professional teams involved.</p>
<p><strong>About Synolia:</strong> Synolia has been a PrestaShop partner for many years. They are also one of the main participants in Open Source PIM, with a privileged partnership with Akeneo, an Open Source PIM publisher who is currently taking a large share of the French and international market (and it’s a French company, too!). Synolia created the PrestaShop-Akeneo connector that is used by many retailers. Based in Lyon (France) and Paris, Synolia is a specialist of ambitious e-commerce, customer relationship management and B.I. projects.</p>
<p>For more information on Akeneo and PrestaShop, see our dedicated micro-site: <a href="http://akeneo.synolia.com/" target="_blank">http://akeneo.synolia.com/</a> or Synolia’s website: <a href="http://www.synolia.com/" target="_blank">www.synolia.com</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/pim-go-faster-managing-product-data/">PIM: go further and faster in managing your product data</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/pim-go-faster-managing-product-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 ways to personalize the customer journey and increase online sales</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-ways-to-personalize-the-customer-journey-and-increase-online-sales/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-ways-to-personalize-the-customer-journey-and-increase-online-sales/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21296</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>75% of consumers say they like it when brands personalize the shopping experience, with 54% going as far as to say that they would consider ending their relationship with a retailer if they weren’t given tailored content and offers. Personalization, then, is clearly a consumer-led trend with a bright future. And with 94% of companies [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-ways-to-personalize-the-customer-journey-and-increase-online-sales/">3 ways to personalize the customer journey and increase online sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>75%</strong> of consumers say they like it when brands personalize the shopping experience, with <strong>54%</strong> going as far as to say that they would consider ending their relationship with a retailer if they weren’t given tailored content and offers. Personalization, then, is clearly a consumer-led trend with a bright future. And with 94% of companies agreeing it “is critical to current and future success” brands seem to understand its importance. But they while they may want to heed the call, do they know how to do it well?<br />
<span id="more-21296"></span><br />
According to analyst firm Gartner, no, they do not. In a recent report they stated that “confusion abounds in the marketplace as to what constitutes personalization”- alarming, considering the potential this trend has to change the ecommerce world.</p>
<p>So, what is personalization? And how can it be applied to your PrestaShop store to make real and important long-term improvements to your business? </p>
<p>Personalization, at its most basic level, is the delivery of tailored content and experiences across every point of the customer journey. In other words, the right content, for the right person, at the right time. </p>
<p>When done right, a long-term strategy aimed at increasing customer lifetime value (CLTV) can yield increases in conversion, average order value, customer retention and overall revenue. The most sophisticated personalization solutions are automated, easy to setup, and simple to optimize and maintain. Despite their relative simplicity, they should be considered a long-term tool to improve your KPIs and customer satisfaction, not a quick fix. Why? Because at the very core personalization is about identifying and forming relationships between customer behavior and product details to be able to determine what a customer is will like and purchase. The more items and traffic your store has, the faster and stronger these relationships will be formed.  </p>
<p>So, you have the traffic, the items and the desire to improve your KPIs. What now? Let’s look at the three levels of personalization and how, in real terms, they can be applied to the customer journey&#8230; </p>
<h4 style="color:#ce0587">Collaborative filtering:</h4>
<p><em>Tailoring the shopping journey according to crowd logic &#8211; for example, best sellers.</em></p>
<p>This type of personalization relies on the assumption that people follow a crowd mentality, led by societal norms, and reinforced by the approval of their peers. It includes the highlighting of ‘best-seller’ and ‘trending’ items, something done not only to give precedence to items most likely to convert, but also to reassure customers that their buying decisions are approved by general consensus.</p>
<h4 style="color:#ce0587">Segmentation:</h4>
<p><em>Targeting individuals belonging to a larger group defined by shared traits- for example, demographic, geo-location or device type.</em></p>
<p>This can include simple changes, such as presetting your site’s language configuration for IP addresses from a certain country, or it may be a logic employed according to more complicated, automated, and algorithmic change. For example, automatically editing the content of an ad to contain a certain style of female clothing for a certain age of female audience. While this category of personalization isn’t truly individualized, it is targeted.</p>
<h4 style="color:#ce0587">One-to-one personalization:</h4>
<p><em>Tailoring the ecommerce experience to individual shoppers, and what purists would state to be the true meaning of personalization- for example, “Recommended for you”.</em></p>
<p>This can be done in real-time according to immediate behavioral changes or based on individualized customer profiles, built up over time using historical data. When profiling a customer, information may be collected across hundreds of data points from several sources, including location, onsite and offsite behavior, and interaction with emails. Information collected can include interests, context, and even where they are in the buying cycle.</p>
<p>Personalization is one trend that can be relevant at every part of the sales funnel &#8211; including customer acquisition, conversion, retention, and finally, delight. The following is an example of a truly personalized journey, an example of what would happen, were you to implement the most personalization strategies. </p>
<h2 style="color:#ce0587">Personalization to drive qualified traffic to your store:</h2>
<p>This primarily involves personalized product-level displays or social adverts. These can either be targeted at specific audiences or aimed at the individual through retargeting. In terms of effectiveness, personalized display ads have a CTR 10x higher than traditional display ads, with the average ROI of Nosto Personalized Facebook Ads clocking in at 36x. </p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/03/dealer-de-coque.png" alt="dealer-de-coque" width="498" height="393" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21300" /></p>
<p><a href="http://dealerdecoque.fr/en/" target="_blank">Dealer de Coque</a> set out to tempt new customers away from their Facebook conversation and to the online store by using <a href="http://www.nosto.com/features/facebook-ads/" target="_blank">personalized Facebook adverts</a> to highlight real-time trending items. These ‘Best Seller’ product-level ads are automatically updated on a regular basis to show the most popular items in the store, and therefore represent items that are most likely to convert. Ads are populated based on real-time user behavior, as well as stock levels – meaning an out-of-stock product is never shown. The highlighting of real-time trending items in this type of prospecting ad has been shown to produce a 13x higher CTR.</p>
<h2 style="color:#ce0587">Personalization to convert:</h2>
<p><em>Automated onsite product recommendations that allow customers a smoother, quicker and tailored journey through your store.</em></p>
<p>According to Infosys, 86% of people say personalization plays a role in their buying decisions, with customers who clicked on personalization elements 125% more likely to buy.</p>
<p>Additionally, you may use pop-ups to deliver time-limited special offers, and one-time discount targeted according to behaviour or customer type. These type of pop-ups have seen a 55% average increase in conversion for first time visitors.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/03/planetfitness-714x1024.png" alt="planetfitness" width="500" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21299" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.planetfitness.com/" target="_blank">Planet Fitness</a> needed a way to offer a highly personalized service while dealing with increased customer demand. With a wide selection of complementary products, it was also important that each customer be able to find exactly what they were looking for, while being exposed to the product range. Using on-site personalization, the company was able to deliver highly-targeted product recommendations based on the brands and categories their customers love, as well as individual shopping behavior. By delivering the most relevant customer experience to each visitor these type of recommendations have been shown to increase conversion by up tp 11%.</p>
<h2 style="color:#ce0587">Personalization to retain customers &amp; create promoters:</h2>
<p><em>Dynamically tailor newsletter content to be unique to each recipient using dynamically editable copy or images, or by including product-level recommendations.</em></p>
<p>Personalization within emails has been shown to improve click-through rates by 14%.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/03/mylittlesquare-573x1024.png" alt="mylittlesquare" width="300" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21297" /></p>
<p>Using <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/remarketing-shopping-cart-abandonment/18349-nostotagging.html" target="_blank">personalized abandoned cart emails</a>, <a href="http://www.mylittlesquare.com/" target="_blank">My Little Square</a> have been able to promote the right products, to the right audience, at the right time &#8211; allowing My Little Square to retain otherwise lost customers. </p>
<p>Email marketing that uses automated offers based on individual user behavior, rather from static product recommendations, has been shown to produce click-through rates 10x higher than the industry standard.</p>
<p>So there you have it: making the shopping experience easier, smoother, more personal and more enjoyable results in happier customers. And ultimately, happy customers buy more, more often and are more loyal. Personalization will help increase conversion rates, average order values and CLTV- which are key metrics that determine the success of your business.If you improve your customer&#8217;s experience at every stage of the sales funnel, you will automatically improve the metrics associated with each of those stages.</p>
<p>To optimize the traffic you have on your site and enjoy the benefits of personalization start your 14-day trial with Nosto <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/remarketing-shopping-cart-abandonment/18349-nostotagging.html" target="_blank">here</a>. </p>
<p><em>Sources: <a href="http://www.aberdeen.com/research/4904/ra-email-marketing/content.aspx" target="_blank">Aberdeen Group</a>, <a href="https://www.nchannel.com/blog/retail-data-ecommerce-statistics/" target="_blank">NChannel blog</a>, <a href="http://www.etailcore.com/blog/personalisation-is-critical/" target="_blank">etailcore</a>, <a href="http://www.getelastic.com/display-retargeting-are-personalized-ads-better-than-generic/" target="_blank">getelastic</a>, <a href="http://www.gigya.com/blog/5-stats-that-prove-businesses-must-personalize-to-win-customers/" target="_blank">gigya</a>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-ways-to-personalize-the-customer-journey-and-increase-online-sales/">3 ways to personalize the customer journey and increase online sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-ways-to-personalize-the-customer-journey-and-increase-online-sales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Spring Cleaning Tips for Your Ecommerce Store: Legal Edition</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-spring-cleaning-tips-ecommerce-store-legal-edition/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-spring-cleaning-tips-ecommerce-store-legal-edition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 10:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21282</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Today, Leah Hamilton from Terms Feed explains how to give your site a little “spring cleaning” to ensure optimum functionality and legal compliance, year-round. Keeping your ecommerce store fresh and up-to-date is important to ensure that it functions well, meets customer needs, and maintains any legal obligations that you may have (such as intellectual property [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-spring-cleaning-tips-ecommerce-store-legal-edition/">3 Spring Cleaning Tips for Your Ecommerce Store: Legal Edition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Today, Leah Hamilton from Terms Feed explains how to give your site a little “spring cleaning” to ensure optimum functionality and legal compliance, year-round.</em></p>
<p>Keeping your ecommerce store fresh and up-to-date is important to ensure that it functions well, meets customer needs, and maintains any legal obligations that you may have (such as intellectual property protection and privacy rules). By examining your ecommerce store up close once a year, you can avoid unpleasant surprises later on.</p>
<p>We’ll take a look at 3 “spring beginnings” you should apply to your ecommerce store to keep your business in top legal condition. First we’ll look at protecting IP, as well as product photos; next we’ll examine your Privacy Policy and some things to note about leveraging old data; finally, we’ll describe some tips for making sure you’re not in breach of anti-spam laws with any marketing emails you may be sending.</p>
<p><span id="more-21282"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #494285">Updating Product Photos and Protecting IP</h2>
<p>Refreshing <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/improve-product-photos-online-store-the-5-mistakes-you-dont-want-commit/">product photos</a> is something that you need to do at least once a year, and even more frequently if your stock changes often.</p>
<h4 style="color: #d80065">False Advertising</h4>
<p>By providing <a href="http://www.efulfillmentservice.com/2012/03/ecommerce-tip-of-the-week-use-great-photos/" target="_blank">accurate, up-to-date product photos</a>, you reduce the likelihood of items being returned for not meeting the accompanying written description. Even better, you’ll avoid legal liability for misleading or false advertising. For example, take a look at these product photo comparisons:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21327" alt="Dress Overexposed" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/03/Dress-Overexposed.jpg" width="900" height="435" /></p>
<p>In this image you can see that using flash has made the first photo look over-exposed and unappealing. The second photo looks softer and nicer, like a mug you would actually want to drink from!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21285" alt="img01" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/03/img01.jpg" width="1024" height="768" /></p>
<p>These images show us how the same product can be presented in wildly different ways, depending on the photography. The first image is blurry, has awkward shadows, is off-kilter, and doesn’t look particularly mouth watering. The second image looks appealing: the lighting is good and the background has been digitally altered.</p>
<p>The above images are good examples of photography can enhance a product’s desirability. But when this is taken too far, you risk crossing the line into false advertising through misleading imagery. While unfortunately a common occurrence, this practice is unacceptable with regard to advertising standards. We see it most often in relation to <a href="http://izismile.com/2009/04/27/fast-food_products_on_ads_and_in_real_life_14_pics.html" target="_blank">fast food advertisements</a> (and the often-disappointing real food). Take a look at this example:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21286" alt="img02" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/03/img02.jpg" width="640" height="256" /></p>
<p>You can protect yourself from these issues by carefully <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/diy-ecommerce-guide-to-gorgeous-product-photography/">taking your own product photos</a> or using a professional photographer to do so.</p>
<h4 style="color: #d80065">Protecting Your IP</h4>
<p>Once you have <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/make-the-most-of-your-product-images-with-prestashop/">created new product photos</a> (whether on your own or with the help of a professional), you need to ensure that you protect your own intellectual property in these images. The type of intellectual property protection we’re referring to here is copyright.</p>
<p>Copyright protects your work from being copied or used by other people. Typically, a work must meet minimal standards of originality in order to qualify for copyright, and the copyright expires after a set period of time (some jurisdictions may allow this to be extended).</p>
<p>Different countries use different tests to determine when copyright “attaches” to a work, although generally the requirements are low. For example, in the UK, &#8220;skill, labour, and judgment&#8221; must have been put into the original work for it to have copyright protection. In every country that has adopted the Berne Convention standards, <a href="https://www.gov.uk/copyright" target="_blank">copyright is automatic</a>, unless the jurisdiction also provides for a system of registration within that country. In that case, registration may be necessary to prove in court that you have a valid copyright, even though you might already have a valid (automatic) copyright.</p>
<h2 style="color: #494285">Leveraging Data and Your Privacy Policy</h2>
<p>Remember to take a look at what data you are still leveraging and using from the previous year. The first thing to do is examine whether it is still relevant and up to date.</p>
<p>Next, look at:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>who has access to the data within your organisation?</li>
<li>do those people need to have access to that data?</li>
<li>is the data still relevant to your purpose for collecting it?</li>
<li>are your previous conclusions (from analysing the data) still relevant?</li>
<li>are you still using the data in the best way for the current market?</li>
<li>do you need to re-analyse the data to pull out new trends to create new business strategies?</li>
</ul>
<p>This is also a good opportunity to refresh your Privacy Policy. We’ve examined Privacy Policies at PrestaShop before, in two parts. The <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/protecting-customer-privacy-prestashop-store-part-1/">first part</a> examined what a Privacy Policy is, and how you can comply with laws in the US and EU. The <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/protecting-customer-privacy-prestashop-store-part-2/">second part</a> looked at displaying your Privacy Policy, and keeping it secure.</p>
<p>If you’re updating your Privacy Policy to comply with those rules, you’ll now need to know how to post an update to your Privacy Policy on your ecommerce store to ensure customers are legally bound by your new version. Your updates must be visible and accessible, and your customers must be informed that an update has been made.</p>
<p>One good way to do this is to send out an email to customers who have signed up, saying your terms have been updated. Here’s an example from <a href="https://bitly.com/" target="_blank">Bitly</a>:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21287" alt="img03" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/03/img03.jpg" width="610" height="929" /></p>
<p>You can see that the message is clear, sets out the changes in an easy-to-read form that customers can understand, and also includes a link to the new Privacy Policy so customers can read it.</p>
<p>Another way is to display a link on your website or blog. Take a look at this example from <a href="http://www.swcredit.com.au/blog-blog-2014-our-privacy-policy-has-changed.html" target="_blank">Southwest Credit</a>:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21288" alt="img04" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/03/img04.jpg" width="997" height="352" /></p>
<p>The key thing to remember here (as established in the legal case of <a href="http://blog.ericgoldman.org/archives/2010/11/another_ruling.htm" target="_blank">Roling v. E*Trade</a>) is that it’s not enough to just upload a copy of the new terms to your website &#8211; you must tell your users that the document has changed or been updated.</p>
<h2 style="color: #494285">Anti-Spam Compliance and Email Marketing</h2>
<p>Finally, make sure you update all of your email templates and segment your marketing lists. Email templates can all-too-often be left behind.</p>
<h4 style="color: #d80065">Email Templates and Anti-Spam Law</h4>
<p>Updating your email templates allows you to ensure compliance with anti-spam legislation, such as CAN-SPAM in the US, the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 in the UK, and the Privacy and Electronic Communication Directive in the EU. These laws cover what you need to do when emailing customers or potential customers to ensure that you are not sending unsolicited or misleading messages. We’ve covered this at PrestaShop before, in our holiday-themed article on anti-spam laws. Take a look at some of the key points <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/anti-spam-time-season/">here</a>.</p>
<p>Remember that one of the most important steps towards compliance you can take when examining your email templates is to check whether they all include an unsubscribe link for any marketing messages that you send out. Another key feature your email templates need is the ability to customize aspects to ensure message accuracy. For example, make sure it is clear to those using the templates that they should change subject headers to reflect the content of the message.</p>
<h4 style="color: #d80065">Segmenting Marketing Lists</h4>
<p><a href="http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/32848/Why-List-Segmentation-Matters-in-Email-Marketing.aspx" target="_blank"> Segmenting marketing lists</a> is important for high quality marketing, as it allows you to exercise a more targeted email strategy that is less likely to be viewed as spam.</p>
<p>There are several <a href="http://smallbiztrends.com/2015/12/segmenting-your-email-lists.html" target="_blank">different ways</a> to segment your customers. For example, you can look at natural groups such as sex, location, or age, or examine trends such as groups of people that have the same spending patterns. The important thing to keep in mind when determining segmentation is that you are not just splitting your customers into groups for the sake of it: remember that the purpose is to segment your customers into categories that make sense in terms of what affects buying behaviour. There’s no point splitting your customers into men and women if your data shows that their buying behaviour for your product is the same.</p>
<p>The primary benefit of customer segmentation is that it allows you to pinpoint which groups are the most and least profitable so you can create targeted marketing campaigns for each of them. This allows you to allocate business marketing resources more prudently, and in a more focused manner.</p>
<h2 style="color: #494285">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Re-examining your product photos, IP protection, data leveraging methods and privacy, as well as anti-spam compliance and email features can help keep your marketing messages fresh and your business practices legally compliant.</p>
<p>Remember to take a look at these key areas every year to ensure that you don’t let something fall behind. While it may appear to be a lot of effort, the benefits are more than worth it.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-spring-cleaning-tips-ecommerce-store-legal-edition/">3 Spring Cleaning Tips for Your Ecommerce Store: Legal Edition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-spring-cleaning-tips-ecommerce-store-legal-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>eCommerce Virtual Staff: 10 Tips To Beef Up Productivity</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-virtual-staff-10-tips-beef-productivity/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-virtual-staff-10-tips-beef-productivity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 13:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21259</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>By 2017, U.S. retail ecommerce sales are expected to hit $434.2 billion, up from $225.5 billion in 2012. It’s safe to say that the pie is getting bigger. Entrepreneurs looking to get a bigger piece of that pie can’t afford to be involved in every last task: updating product descriptions, data exports, inventory management, and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-virtual-staff-10-tips-beef-productivity/">eCommerce Virtual Staff: 10 Tips To Beef Up Productivity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By 2017, U.S. retail ecommerce sales are <a href="http://www.statista.com/statistics/272391/us-retail-e-commerce-sales-forecast/" target="_blank">expected to hit $434.2 billion</a>, up from $225.5 billion in 2012. It’s safe to say that the pie is getting bigger.</p>
<p>Entrepreneurs looking to get a bigger piece of that pie can’t afford to be involved in every last task: updating product descriptions, data exports, inventory management, and social media are all things you need to hand off if you want to progress to the next level.</p>
<p>Managing a virtual staff can relieve some of the day-to-day activities that suck up your time. Just don’t make the mistake of thinking your virtual assistants (VAs) don’t need to be trained and managed.</p>
<p>Here are ten tips and tools to get the most of our your virtual staff.<br />
<span id="more-21259"></span></p>
<h4 style="color: #e78199">1. Know What (and How) to Delegate</h4>
<p>Know your strengths, and know what you need your team to do. Regardless of how many ecommerce staff members you have, it pays to know where your time is best spent, and the strengths of each team member. Delegate tasks according to what needs to be done, but also to who will do them best.</p>
<h4 style="color: #e78199">2. Foster a Culture of Teamwork and Unity</h4>
<p>This is easy to do when everyone comes together in an office every day, but not so much when a team is spread out across the country or even the world. While it’s important to consider the time differences between geographic locations, do your best to provide a place where employees can come together as if they were at the water cooler chatting with one another. You can do this by creating a group Skype conversation, a secret Facebook group, or your own internal social network with a tool like <a href="https://podio.com/site/en" target="_blank">Podio</a>.</p>
<p>Host virtual meetings with Skype, Google Hangouts, or another tool like <a href="http://www.gotomeeting.com/" target="_blank">GoToMeeting</a>. Timing can be difficult if you’re working on the other side of the world, so make sure recordings are available to view later for those members who couldn’t attend live.</p>
<h4 style="color: #e78199">3. Set Up VA Access Rights</h4>
<p>PrestaShop makes it easy <a href="http://doc.prestashop.com/display/PS16/Profile+permissions" target="_blank">to configure your store access rights</a> for each member of your team. Have an extensive catalog and need help updating it? Employee accounts allow you to control what team members can access. As your VA gains trust, you can increase their workload, and access level.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21379" alt="adm012-permissions-en2-161" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/02/adm012-permissions-en2-161-1024x482.png" width="700" height="329" /></p>
<h4 style="color: #e78199">4. Protect Your Cloud Data</h4>
<p>These days, everything goes on the cloud. Even Prestashop. Controlling access levels is a must-needed first step in managing your ecommerce business. But what about other cloud-based software that your VAs access on their personal devices?</p>
<p>Microsoft SCCM can manage your virtual staff’s access levels to all of your cloud-based applications on their devices. If you’re unfamiliar with how to use a system like this for your ecommerce store, there are user friendly <a href="https://www.cbtnuggets.com/it-training/microsoft-sccm-70-243-r2" target="_blank">tutorials about Microsoft SCCM</a>. With a single management console, you can manage Macs, PCs, servers, and cloud-based mobile devices running Windows®, iOS®, or Android™, all from a central location.</p>
<h4 style="color: #e78199">5. Have an Onboarding and Training Process</h4>
<p>Create a series of videos to train your team on how to do the various tasks associated with the job. Have documents like W9s, contracts, non-disclosure agreements, and more, ready to go for your new hires. Consider using a platform like <a href="https://www.docusign.com/" target="_blank">DocuSign </a>to handle signing documentation digitally.</p>
<h4 style="color: #e78199">6. Centralize Time Tracking and Payroll</h4>
<p>With platforms like Tick, you can <a href="https://www.tickspot.com/project-budget-tracking" target="_blank">budget and track your team’s time</a>. If you’re really worried about whether your team is actually working, use a tool like <a href="https://hubstaff.com/" target="_blank">Hubstaff</a>. You can add multiple team members and projects, and handle payments from within the system, to make it easier for everyone.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21266" alt="img02" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/02/img02.png" width="490" height="290" /></p>
<h4 style="color: #e78199">7. Offer Rewards for a Job Well Done</h4>
<p>You may not be able to offer a full benefits package like the folks at Google or Facebook, but incentives can go a long way toward keeping your employees happy. A <a href="http://www.globoforce.com/resources/research-reports/shrmgloboforce-fall-2012-report-the-business-impact-of-employee-recognition/" target="_blank">2012 study</a> showed that 41% of companies that use peer-to-peer recognition programs have seen an increase in customer satisfaction, so it really pays to keep your employees happy. That same study also revealed an average of 23.4% lower turnover rate.</p>
<p>Consider offering cash bonuses, gift cards, or even tangible rewards like tablets, computers, and gaming consoles to employees who are going above and beyond the call of duty to make your business better.</p>
<h4 style="color: #e78199">8. Educate Your Team About Fraud</h4>
<p>When it comes to <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-smartest-checklists-to-manage-your-online-store/">managing your store</a>, fraud is no doubt going to rear its ugly head at some point. Your team needs to know what kinds of things to look for, and what can happen to the business as a result of fraudulent transactions. Hackers often see the tiny fish in the sea as the easier targets. If your team knows what to look for, they can help stop it in its tracks, saving you time and frustration.</p>
<h4 style="color: #e78199">9. Be Available to Your Team</h4>
<p>Make sure all members of your team can reach you when they need to. Being available to answer questions, or to provide additional support can help keep the lines of communication open. When your team knows they can come to you, you’ll be less likely to run into issues because they were afraid to come to you something before it became a problem.</p>
<h4 style="color: #e78199">10. Have a Plan to Address Turnover</h4>
<p>If you have the staff of your dreams, that’s wonderful, but you can’t count on it being that way forever. Virtual staff members, whether they work for you full or part time, may find other opportunities for growth and advancement, which means you need to be ready to replace any member of your staff at any time. You may find team members aren’t performing the way you need them to, and you can only give someone so many chances before you need to replace them.</p>
<p>Know where to look for new workers, whether you’re hiring them as freelancers, or full fledged employees. LinkedIn is a great place to start, but you can also post ads on Craigslist, or turn to freelance marketplaces like Guru in a pinch.</p>
<p>Managing a virtual team for any business, especially ecommerce, isn’t for the faint of heart. But, fortunately for you, even if you’re working with a small budget, there are plenty of affordable tools available to make the job easier on everyone.</p>
<hr align="left" width="20%" />
<p>Darren has an MBA in Internet Marketing, but hangs his hat on a decade of experience in the trenches. Check out <a href="https://selfstartr.com/" target="_blank">Selfstartr </a>to learn more about ecommerce. Follow him on <a href="https://twitter.com/DarrenDeMatas" target="_blank">Twitter </a>and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/internetmarketingmba" target="_blank">LinkedIn</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-virtual-staff-10-tips-beef-productivity/">eCommerce Virtual Staff: 10 Tips To Beef Up Productivity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-virtual-staff-10-tips-beef-productivity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get started with video marketing for eCommerce</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-started-video-marketing-ecommerce/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-started-video-marketing-ecommerce/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 13:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21233</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>A photo might be worth a thousand words, but a product video is worth much more in terms of engagement and conversions. 96% of consumers find video content useful when shopping online. eCommerce merchants featuring product videos on their sites report an increase in conversion rates of up to 85%. Other benefits of video for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-started-video-marketing-ecommerce/">Get started with video marketing for eCommerce</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A photo might be worth a thousand words, but a product video is worth much more in terms of engagement and conversions. <a href="http://www.reelseo.com/consumers-purchase-video/" target="_blank">96% of consumers</a> find video content useful when shopping online. eCommerce merchants featuring product videos on their sites report an increase in conversion rates of <a href="http://blog.crazyegg.com/2015/03/05/videos-boost-conversion-rates/" target="_blank">up to 85%</a>. Other <a href="http://blog.goodvid.io/5-benefits-of-having-product-videos-on-ecommerce-site?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=video%20marketing" target="_blank">benefits of video for ecommerce</a> include: prolonged session duration, more site pages visited, improved conversion rates and more site traffic.</p>
<p>Let’s take a look at some of the basic things to consider when developing a video marketing strategy for your business.<br />
<span id="more-21233"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#474474">How to select the right video marketing strategy for you</h2>
<p>Before you dive into the creative aspect of video marketing, you should evaluate what kind of video strategy works best for you. What do you expect to achieve with videos on your site? What kind of resources do you have in terms of time, money and skills? The role you envision for videos on your site and the effort you are prepared to invest in video marketing should guide your strategy. There are three main routes you can take:</p>
<h4 style="color:#474474">1. Make your own videos</h4>
<p>Creating your own videos is the most resource-demanding strategy, but also the most rewarding one in terms of giving a voice to your brand. If you are selling products under your own label, then making your own videos makes sense, as this strategy allows you to promote your own brand, values and vision.</p>
<h4 style="color:#474474">2. Source videos from brands, experts and users</h4>
<p>Not all online merchants have the drive to create their own videos, and that’s fine. If you are pressed for time and resources or simply don’t feel comfortable in front of the camera, make use of existing videos about the products and brands you sell. YouTube and other video-sharing platforms are overflowing with <a href="https://goodvid.io/video-gallery?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=video%20marketing" target="_blank">videos by brands</a>, experts and users that are available for re-sharing on ecommerce sites&#8211;and, best of all, they’re free. This is a great way to test how shoppers react to videos on your site without making major commitments to video production, especially if you’ve never experimented with video marketing before.</p>
<h4 style="color:#474474">3. Combine your own videos with curated videos</h4>
<p>Finally, take the best of both worlds and offer your shoppers a mix of your own videos and those curated from other sources. This is a great way to diversify your video content, keep shoppers engaged, and demonstrate your product expertise.</p>
<h2 style="color:#474474">Select the right type of videos</h2>
<p>After you have selected the right video strategy for your business, it’s time to think about the kind of video content your shoppers will value the most. Videos should engage shoppers with interesting stories about the products and motivate them to click the “add to cart” button. Some of the best types of videos for ecommerce are:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><strong>Product review videos.</strong> They let shoppers know what the main features and benefits of the product are, as well as how it performs in action. These videos set expectations about a product before shoppers commit to a purchase and help prevent returns.</li>
<li><strong>How-to tutorial videos.</strong> Instructional videos showcasing <a href="http://blog.goodvid.io/how-online-retailers-can-leverage-how-to-video-content/?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=video%20marketing" target="_blank">how to assemble, use and maintain products</a> are especially valuable for complex products such as consumer electronics, appliances, cosmetics and baby products.</li>
<li><strong>Unboxing videos.</strong> Having a video which demonstrates product packaging and how it’s unwrapped helps shoppers visualize their purchases better. These videos help reduce shopper anxiety and spur interest in the product.</li>
</ul>
<p>When selecting videos for your site, think about the kinds of questions shoppers are likely to have about your products and let the video answer them. Remember, video should act as a virtual salesperson on your ecommerce site, so choose videos that will help tackle any uncertainties shoppers might have.</p>
<h2 style="color:#474474">Best practices for product videos for eCommerce</h2>
<p>When done right, videos can bring tangible improvements to engagement and conversion rates of ecommerce sites. Here are some practical tips online merchants should have in mind when developing video marketing tactics:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Get inspired.</strong> Research YouTube for videos about the products and brands you’re selling or about products in the same category. Search for videos by brands, users, experts and retailers. Take notes on the information they provide, the style and length of their videos and calls to action. Use these insights to decide what kind of videos you could make or curate for your site.</li>
<li><strong>Start by adding videos to your most lucrative products.</strong> If you haven’t used videos on your site before, it’s a good idea to start with your best-selling products or product pages with the highest traffic. This will enable you to quickly gather data about the effects of video on engagement and conversion.</li>
<li><strong>Bring videos closer to conversion points.</strong> If you want to track how video affects your “add-to-cart” conversion rates, then make sure you add videos directly to product pages, rather than category pages, to maximize their effect on the purchase intent.</li>
<li><strong>Make video easy to spot.</strong> Place product videos alongside product photos and product description. This grabs shoppers’ attention right away and prompts them to engage with the content. Try to place video above the fold when possible. Avoid placing videos at the bottom of the page, as this makes it difficult for shoppers to discover them.</li>
<li><strong>Add multiple videos to product pages.</strong> You have multiple product photos on your pages, so why not have multiple videos as well? Try a combination of different types of videos to engage shoppers. Mix up your own videos with user-generated videos, customer testimonials and product reviews to give shoppers an authentic experience. Don’t be afraid to test different <a href="http://blog.goodvid.io/5-ecommerce-video-trends-for-2016/?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=video%20marketing" target="_blank">video gallery</a> options to discover your winning formula.</li>
<li><strong>Make sure videos display well on mobile.</strong> We live in a mobile world and shoppers want a seamless experience, no matter what devices they use to access your online store. Don’t forget to apply responsive design to videos as well, so shoppers can see videos in full quality when browsing your site from mobile.</li>
</ol>
<h2 style="color:#474474">What’s next?</h2>
<p>Once you’ve drafted your video marketing strategy, make sure to test how well video works on your ecommerce site. Here are some of the things you should be monitoring:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>How do shoppers behave on pages with video versus pages without video?</li>
<li>What percentage of shoppers actually watches video?</li>
<li>How long do shoppers engage with video?</li>
<li>How do videos impact session duration and the number of pages visited?</li>
<li>What are the conversion rates on pages with video versus pages without video?</li>
</ul>
<p>Answering these questions and monitoring shopper behavior will help you understand which approach is right for you. Video is an excellent addition to your marketing efforts, so keep on experimenting and perfecting it. If you haven’t started with video yet, don’t miss out on the opportunity to give your shoppers a great customer experience with videos they’ll love to watch!</p>
<h2 style="color:#474474">About the author</h2>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-21235" alt="miljana-mitic" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/02/miljana-mitic.png" width="100" height="100" /></p>
<p>Miljana Mitic is the Content Marketing Manager at <a href="https://goodvid.io/" target="_blank">Goodvidio</a>, a SaaS solution that helps online stores bring the best product videos from social media to their product pages. Miljana has a PhD in social media marketing and writes about how online stores can make the most out of product videos. She loves discovering new restaurants, reading, playing with dogs and watching YouTube haul videos.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-started-video-marketing-ecommerce/">Get started with video marketing for eCommerce</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-started-video-marketing-ecommerce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Social Media Case Study: Take a ride with Wobybi</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-media-case-study-take-ride-wobybi/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-media-case-study-take-ride-wobybi/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 13:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21230</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Meet Wobybi, this week’s featured PrestaShop merchant. We sat down with Alvaro Basterra, the company’s founder, to learn more about how they use social media to promote their online store. Let’s find out what he has to say! Tell us about Wobybi. Wobybi is a custom bike brand based in Spain. We are specialized in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-media-case-study-take-ride-wobybi/">Social Media Case Study: Take a ride with Wobybi</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meet <a href="http://www.wobybi.es/" target="_blank">Wobybi</a>, this week’s featured PrestaShop merchant. We sat down with Alvaro Basterra, the company’s founder, to learn more about how they use social media to promote their online store. Let’s find out what he has to say!<br />
<span id="more-21230"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#88ae01">Tell us about Wobybi.</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.wobybi.es/" target="_blank">Wobybi</a> is a custom bike brand based in Spain. We are specialized in building one-of-a kind bikes, so our online store, which runs on PrestaShop 1.5.2, has been designed to allow every customer to design their own bike. They first pick a base model, then customize each piece in their preferred color, and finally review and confirm their order. </p>
<h2 style="color:#88ae01">How has social media impacted your business?</h2>
<p>Social networks are a great way to meet and connect with our community. We try to build a personal relationship with our fans. We like to encourage them to interact with us and comment, share, and send us their pictures and videos.</p>
<p>Because we sell personalized products, interacting with our community is particularly important. We use it to provide unique, exclusive and personal service to each of our customers.</p>
<h2 style="color:#88ae01">Which social media channels and tools do you use?</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/Wobybi" target="_blank">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/wobybi/" target="_blank">Instagram</a> work well because they are very visual and enable us to showcase our product photos. We also use <a href="https://twitter.com/wobybi" target="_blank">Twitter</a>, but more as a portal for customer service and sharing information. </p>
<p>Our favorite tools include: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><a href="https://hootsuite.com/" target="_blank">Hootsuite</a> to schedule publications</li>
<li><a href="https://sumall.com/" target="_blank">SumAll</a> to receive a daily and weekly summary of notifications</li>
<li><a href="https://mention.com/en/" target="_blank">Mention</a> to learn more about people who mention us</li>
<li><a href="https://feedly.com/i/welcome" target="_blank">Feedly</a> to read news on our sector</li>
<li><a href="https://bitly.com/" target="_blank">Bitly</a> to shorten URLs and monitor the number of clicks</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color:#88ae01">Where do you get inspiration for social media content?</h2>
<p>We have someone dedicated to managing all of our social media channels full time. Our posts are based on a strategy we’ve defined in our marketing plan: our goal is to create original and quality content to attract new potential customers. Ideas and inspiration can come from anywhere &#8212; Instagram, Pinterest, meetings, brainstorming. The most important thing for merchants to remember is to focus campaigns and not forget about the ultimate goal!</p>
<h2 style="color:#88ae01">Can you share some tips with other merchants starting out on social media? </h2>
<p>The most important thing is to establish a strategy for each social network and only focus on a couple in the beginning; there’s no use just “being there to be there.” Include top quality content tailored to your specific customer base. We use a lot of content that features GIF or videos, which suits our demographic very well. Finally, and most importantly, respond to each question and comment you receive on social media.</p>
<hr width="20%" align="left">
<p>Ready to launch your own social media campaign for your ecommerce business? Check out part 1 of our series with HootSuite Social Media Coach for DACH &amp; UK, Hanna Oeljeschlaeger, <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media/">on supporting your ecommerce business with social media</a>.</p>
<p>Don’t own an online store yet? What are you waiting for get started to day with <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop</a>. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-media-case-study-take-ride-wobybi/">Social Media Case Study: Take a ride with Wobybi</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-media-case-study-take-ride-wobybi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Retargeting Basics for Online Merchants</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/retargeting-basics-online-merchants/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/retargeting-basics-online-merchants/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 13:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21219</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>As online shoppers, we’ve all experienced it: while window shopping on a website, you decide you’re not quite ready to make a purchase and go back to skimming Buzzfeed articles. As you continue to browse the internet, you notice the products you just finished browsing hovering at the edge of your screen. How did this [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/retargeting-basics-online-merchants/">Retargeting Basics for Online Merchants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As online shoppers, we’ve all experienced it: while window shopping on a website, you decide you’re not quite ready to make a purchase and go back to skimming Buzzfeed articles. As you continue to browse the internet, you notice the products you just finished browsing hovering at the edge of your screen. How did this website know you were just ogling those products? If you’re an online merchant, you probably can’t help but ask yourself, would this work for <em>my</em> <a href="http://prestashop.com/">online store</a>? The answer is yes, probably. We invited Garrett Gan from <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/" target="_blank">Thalamus</a>, a digital advertising review website, to give us his insight.<br />
<span id="more-21219"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#353466">1. What is Retargeting?</h2>
<p>Retargeting is a type of advertising that is only shown to people after they have visited your online store. Here’s how it works: you place a pixel (or a single line of code) on your website, which will drop a tracking cookie onto a user&#8217;s browser. With this tracking cookie, <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/display/retargeting" target="_blank">retargeting companies</a> are able to see where the user travels across multiple websites on the internet, and serve them ads accordingly. </p>
<p>The best analogy for this is the tracking of animals using tags, which allows scientists to observe their behavior; in this case, the tag is placed on a consumer&#8217;s&#8217; web browser so that later on, you can serve ads that correspond to their behavior. </p>
<p>One of the best use cases for retargeting is to serve ads to users that have looked at a specific product on your website &#8211; shoes, jeans, t-shirts, trinkets &#8211; and serve them ads for that exact product after they have left (and haven&#8217;t bought yet) with a small discount to entice them to come back to complete the purchase. </p>
<h2 style="color:#353466">2. What types of companies use retargeting? Why?</h2>
<p>All types of companies use retargeting, including those in eCommerce, mobile apps, B2B sites &#8212; even advertising companies!</p>
<p>Retargeting is a powerful tool for communicating with users that have already interacted with your website, to further add value to their experience. </p>
<p>It also makes their web browsing experience more relevant, as the ads you serve will be for specific items they have already browsed, now with discounts and/or giveaways. Without this technology, merchants are now left to decide which products could be relevant for a user. </p>
<p>When retargeting first came out, it was sometimes seen by consumers as “creepy,” but many companies have adopted the tactic for years and has come to be a rather widely accepted practice.</p>
<h2 style="color:#353466">3. How much does it cost to run a retargeting campaign?</h2>
<p>Online merchants can start for as low as $100 per week (or even less) with companies like <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/ad_partners/adroll" target="_blank">AdRoll</a>, or <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/ad_partners/retargeter" target="_blank">Retargeter</a>. There are also larger companies like <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/ad_partners/tellapart" target="_blank">TellApart</a>, <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/ad_partners/criteo" target="_blank">Criteo</a>, or <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/ad_partners/simpli-fi" target="_blank">Simpli.fi</a> that offer more robust features like dynamic creative optimization (changing ads algorithmically to serve the highest performing one), or Product Catalog Feeds (where a consumer can see items similar to the item they just viewed on the e-commerce website).</p>
<h2 style="color:#353466">4. How can online merchants get started with retargeting?</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s a good practice for merchants of all sizes to start running year-round retargeting campaigns. Many eCommerce companies have increased the number of actual conversions from consumers, simply by offering a small discount in a retargeting ad if a user abandoned their cart.</p>
<p>Once merchants are more familiar with how to maximize conversions from regular retargeting ads, then they can move to more sophisticated mechanisms, such as dynamic creative optimization, product feed catalogs (both mentioned above), as well as working with <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/display/ad-network" target="_blank">ad networks</a> to drive new customers to the site.</p>
<hr align="left" width="20%">
<p>Get started today by checking out reviews on retargeting companies like AdRoll and Retargeter on <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/" target="_blank">Thalamus</a>. Then jump in and launch your first retargeting campaign. Already running a campaign? Share your tips and advice in the comments below. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/retargeting-basics-online-merchants/">Retargeting Basics for Online Merchants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/retargeting-basics-online-merchants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
